几周前 一个无形的穹顶从天而降
A few weeks ago, an invisible dome crashed down
笼罩着切斯特磨坊镇 把我们和外面的世界隔离
on Chester's Mill, cutting us off from the rest of the world.
穹顶为何出现 前方还有什么谜团
Why the dome is here or what mysteries lie ahead,
我们仍不清楚
we still don't know.
每天它都在挑战我们的极限
Every day it tests our limits,
让我们展现人性最美和最丑恶的一面
bringing out the best and the worst in us.
有人说我们会永远被困在这里
Some say we'll be stuck here forever,
但我们不会放弃寻找到出路
but we will never stop fighting to find a way out.
梅勒尼 克洛斯 1988年
Melanie Cross, 1988.
这是 我
It's... me.
这像是一种能量源
BIG JIM: It's some kind of energy source.
放开那个蛋
That egg needs to go now.
梅勒尼
Melanie!
到顶点镇的路被切断了
The way to Zenith is blocked?
不仅仅是被切断 是完全消失了
Oh, it's more than blocked... it's gone.
我们又能重新成为一家人了
And then we can be a family again.
-你这个骗子 -你和那个为了蛋
- You're a liar! - You're working for the
把我们困住的人是一伙的
guy who held us captive over the egg.
-吉姆 -莱尔
- Jim! - Lyle?
既然我们回来了
PAULINE: Now that we're back,
不管发生什么 我们都需要莱尔
whatever's gonna happen, we need Lyle.
穹顶正在收缩
The dome's contracting.
你是说它在缩小
You mean, it's shrinking?
我不知道为什么 但它一会缩小一会又停止
I don't know why, but it keeps starting and stopping.
至少它不再旋转和颠倒气候了
At least the dome stopped spinning and inverting the atmosphere.
所以气温才会升高
That's why the temperature's warmed up.
没错 但现在它在缩小
Yeah, but now it's shrinking.
一开始是地震
First, that earthquake struck,
然后这里又变得超级冷 现在又在缩小
then it got super-cold in here, and now this.
你觉得苍穹会不断进化吗
Do you think the dome could be evolving?
最终会变成什么
And into what?
我 我也不知道
I d... I don't know.
怎么又开始了
Why is it moving again?
我会查明清楚的 好吗
Look, I will figure it out, okay?
现在先通知告诉大家
In the meantime, spread the word
让大家在镇中心集合
to get people to the center of town.
用对讲机或者到他们家里都行
Use walkies, go to their houses.
让大家都过去 马上
Just get them there... now.
在这个世界上 任何事物
To everything there is a season,
都有一套自己的生长时期
and a time to every purpose under the heaven...
出生的时期 死亡的时期
A time to be born, a time to die,
种植的时期
a time to plant,
把种植物给
a time to pluck that which...
拔掉的时期
- - is planted.
谢天谢地 又暖和起来了
Thank God it's warming up again.
无论发生什么 我们都会一起克服的
Well, whatever happens, we'll get through it together,
只要你想要的话
if that's what you want.
你听到了吗
Did you hear that?
听到了
Yeah.
不可能是蛋的原因 是吧
Can't be the egg, though. Right?
嗯 是其他原因
No, it's something else.
莱尔
Lyle.
经历了这么多事情 你应该好好休息一下
You should be resting after everything you've been through.
听到了吗
You hear that?
什么
Huh?
我想我们马上就要完蛋了
I think we're all gonna be resting pretty soon.
吉姆告诉你我看见什么了吗
Did Jim tell you about what I saw?
在我回来的路上我清楚的看见了地狱
A fresh vision of hell on my way back here.
他告诉我了
Yeah, he did.
你经历了太多事了
You've been through a lot.
所以你才需要好好休息
Which is all the more reason for you to rest.
走廊那边有一张小床 跟我来
There's a cot down this hallway. Come on.
到哪我都会跟着你的 波林
I'll... I'll follow you anywhere, Pauline.
嗨
Hi.
嘿
Hey.
你醒了
You're awake.
能见到你真是太好了
It's good to see you, too.
感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
好多了
Better.
我觉得
I think.
好像变暖和了
It seems warmer.
寒潮已经过去了
Cold snap's over.
但是
But?
詹姆士 我能感觉到有些事情还是不对劲
James, I can tell something else is wrong.
穹顶正在向内收缩
I think the dome is closing in around us.
什么
What?
我们会想办法阻止它的
We're gonna figure out how to stop it.
也会让你好起来
And we'll find out how to get you better.
其实 我觉得
Actually, I... I think I know
我可能知道答案在哪了
where I might be able to get some answers.
那就去吧
Go.
我没事的
I'll be fine.
我会找人来陪你的
I'll send someone to sit with you.
很好 过来 从这个方向去高中学校
All right, come one. Around this way. Get to the high school...
-记住了吗 那里很安全
- All right? You'll be safe there.
-芭比 你看到了吗
- JOE : Barbie, you seeing this?
是的 乔 我知道穹顶怎么了
Yeah, Joe, I-I see what's happening with the dome,
我现在正在通知大家离开自己的家
all right? I'm just helping people out of their homes.
那我们在学校集合
Okay, let's regroup back at the school.
等会再和你讲
I'll talk to you soon.
你应该带着那个
You should take that.
他是你丈夫
He was your husband.
那都是过去的事了
That was my old life.
能否帮忙把波林的日记递给我
Can you, uh, pass me Pauline's journal?
就在那里
Just there.
穹顶让我们失去了太多
The dome has taken so much from all of us.
现在又发生了这样的事
Now this.
只要我们还活着就好
All that matters is that we survive.
我们会活下去的
And we're going to.
我们必须竭力活下去
We're gonna give it our damndest.
走吧
Let's go.
- 天哪 已经接近我们这边了 - 走这边
- Oh, my God, it's close. - Okay, let's go this way.
快走
Let's go!
听说穹顶正在缩小
Did I hear that the dome is contracting?
是的 我亲眼看到的
Yeah, I saw it with my own eyes.
速度有多快
How fast is it moving?
我还正在计算着 吉姆
I'm still doing the calculations, Jim.
你现在要做的就是让大家保持镇定 然后
So, just do what you do best, keep people calm, and...
嘿
Hey.
欢迎来到全新的噩梦
Welcome to our new nightmare.
穹顶开始明显收缩了
That's stating the obvious.
按照它现在断断续续的收缩速度
I figured out that at its present rate of stopping and starting,
-过不了多久穹顶就会 -完全把我们挤成肉酱
- it won't be long before the dome... - Crushes us completely?
-给我 我来拿 -谢谢
- Here, I'll take that. - Thanks.
每栋房子 每棵树 每一寸土地
The way every house, tree and square foot of dirt
都会向我们这里堆积过来
is gonna pile up inside here,
墙还没到这来我们都会死
we'll be dead long before the walls get to us.
真是难以置信
I just can't believe that.
大吉姆把蛋扔下悬崖了
Big Jim threw the egg off the cliff,
这也就证明那个蛋就是穹顶的能量源
I'd say that proves it's the dome's power source.
不 我是说 我不敢相信穹顶会让我们都没命
No, I mean, that the dome would kill us all.
噢 难道穹顶告诉过你它是来保护我们的吗
Oh, because the dome told you it's here to protect us, right?
你觉得我是在胡思乱想吗
You think I imagined that?
谁知道 你最好有证据证明
I don't know. It would be nice to have some proof.
我很感谢你所做的一切 好吗
Look, I appreciate what you do, all right?
你帮助了大家
You've helped all of us.
但是根据我们所看到的一切
But maybe with everything that we've seen,
也许你该承认事情并不是你所想的那么简单
you could admit there's more going on here.
-好了 我 -现在没时间争论这些
- Okay, I'm d... - BARBIE: Now's not the time to debate this.
知道吗
All right?
你说的对
Okay, you're right.
打扰了
Excuse me.
帮大家安顿下来吧
Let's help everybody settle in.
芭比 茱莉亚
Barbie, Julia!
你们很安全 真是太好了
I'm glad you guys are safe.
我可不这么认为
I'm not so sure.
什么意思
What do you mean?
是亨特 他还有些话要说
Hunter, here, has something he would like to confess.
对吧 亨特
Isn't that right, Hunter?
当我跟着你从顶点镇回来的时候 我其实
Look, when I came back from Zenith with you, I was...
我在偷偷的替你爸办事
I was secretly working for your dad.
什么
What?
他勒索我 让我监视你们
He blackmailed me into spying on you...
想办法把蛋弄到顶点镇去
to find a way to get the egg to Zenith.
我没这么做  因为大吉姆先把蛋扔了
Which I never got to do, because Big Jim tossed it first.
我是站在你这边的 我发誓
Look, I am on your side, I swear!
芭比 是真的
Barbie, it's true.
穹顶外有个军事人员想用蛋做实验
Hunter stopped that military guy outside the dome
亨特阻止了他
from doing experiments on the egg,
因为他知道那样会伤害到梅勒尼
because he knew it was hurting Melanie.
如果我们想不出办法让穹顶停止收缩的话
There's gonna be a lot more people hurt
会有更多的人受到伤害的
if we don't find a way to stop these wall from shrinking.
芭比 我真的很抱歉
Barbie, I'm really sorry!
闭上你的嘴
You don't get to talk!
你们两个去外面帮忙
You two go help out.
你要去哪里吗
You going somewhere?
我说 出去帮忙
I said... go help out.
好吧
Okay.
视频字幕由 SSK字幕组 制作发布
字幕只供学习 请勿做任何商业行为
敬请关注新浪微博@SSK字幕组
好的
Fine.
翻译：Rubens 冬可可 爱吃 Jophy     校对：Jophy
你还好吗
You good?
我去看看梅勒尼
I'll keep an eye on Melanie.
-你要干什么 -闭嘴 只管走路
- What are you doing? - Shut up and walk.
后期：hhjie     时间轴：阿黎     总监：Jophy
跟我走
Let's go.
穹顶之下
第二季  第十二集
本
Ben?
嘿
Hey.
你还好吗
You okay?
一切都完了 诺瑞
It's over, Norrie.
不 不会的
No, it's not.
我刚刚看见五金店老板的车
I just saw the guy who owned the hardware store
被穹顶给挤扁了
get his car crushed when the dome smashed into it.
-他人呢 -死了
- Is he okay? - He's dead.
过不了多久 我们也都会死的
Before too long, we're all gonna be dead, too.
不 我们不会的
No, we're not...
我们一定会找到方法出去的
because we're gonna find a way out of here somehow, someway.
我们不会死在这里
We are not gonna die in here.
你知道我为什么认为一切都会结束吗
You know how I know it's all over?
为什么
How?
因为之前还在抱怨说讨厌这个地方的那个女的
The girl who bitched and moaned about how much she hates
现在却跟我说一切都会没事的
this place is now telling me everything's gonna be okay.
- 诺瑞 走吧 - 干嘛
- Norrie, let's go. - Why?
我看见芭比带着亨特离开学校了
I saw Barbie leading Hunter away from the school.
芭比看起来很不爽
Barbie did not look happy.
-他们要去哪 -不知道
- Where are they going? - I don't know,
所以我们必须跟着他们
that's why we have to follow them.
不管他们要做什么
Well, whatever they're up to,
很明显 芭比不希望我们跟着他们
Barbie obviously didn't want us coming along.
但如果是芭比的话
But if it's Barbie, he's
他很有可能会想到办法阻止发生的这一切
probably got a plan to stop what's happening.
你难道不想知道他要干嘛吗
Don't you want to see what he's up to?
但是为什么我们要回家
But why do we have to go home?
你以前的画也许会告诉我们
Because maybe one of your old paintings shows us
怎样才能让穹顶停止缩小
how we can stop the dome from contracting.
我是说 它预言了穹顶的出现
I mean, it showed it coming down.
也预言了粉色星星的坠落
It showed the pink stars falling.
你去看看吧 不过我可能待在这更有用
Go, have a look, but I could be of more use here.
怎么 为了让莱尔好受点
What, comforting Lyle?
你觉得是这样吗
Is that what this is about?
他简直是疯了 他就是个傻子
He's out of his gourd. His his was pretty soft to begin with.
你后悔救他了么
Are you sorry you saved him from drowning?
没有 我是说 你想让他活着 我就这么做
No, I mean, you wanted him here, and, you know, I did it for you.
-新借口 -什么意思
- That's a new one. - What do you mean?
毕业舞会的那天晚上
That night at the Senior Dance, when Lyle got drunk
莱尔喝醉了拉着我进入舞池的时候
and dragged me onto the dance floor, you said...
你说我不应该接近他
the last place I should be is anywhere near him.
就这样你还是花了六个月才跟他分手
Still took you six months to dump him.
毕竟还是分手了
But I did... eventually.
所以 让我们一起解决这个事吧
So, let's go solve this together.
我要见唐 芭芭拉 立刻马上
不行 先告诉我情况
詹姆斯 你在这里干嘛
James, what are you doing here?
-我来看看梅勒尼 -她好点了么
- It's about Melanie. - Is she better?
她装作很好的样子 但是我还是很担心
She tries to act like it, but I'm still worried.
-等下 谁是梅勒尼 -不关你的事
- Wa-Wait, who's Melanie? - None of your business.
-我得私下和你谈谈 等等 谁是梅勒尼
- I need to talk to you in pri... - N-N-N-No, who is Melanie?
你见过她的 梅勒尼 克洛斯
You've seen her around... Melanie Cross.
梅勒尼 克洛斯 她不是你的朋友么
Melanie Cross, wasn't that a friend of yours?
-她不是25年前就失踪了么 -她死了
- Didn't she go missing 25 years ago? - She died.
死了 那她怎么回来了
She died? W-Wh... How's she back?
因为穹顶 它
The dome, it...
吉姆 是真的 梅勒尼 克洛斯又活过来了
Jim, it's true... Melanie Cross is alive again.
只是这次 她病的很重
Except this time, she's really sick.
我们从彻斯特磨坊镇回来的时候
When we came back into Chester's Mill,
我在陨石坑那边见过她
I had a vision of Melanie in the crater.
-她看起来 很憔悴 -看起来像是病了吗
- She looked... odd. - Like she was sick?
可能是 我握住她手的时候 她似乎好点儿
Maybe, but when I took her hand, she seemed better.
然后呢
Okay, then what happened?
然后我就漂在水面上了
Then I surfaced in the lake.
拜托 你得使劲想想她的样子 然后画下来
Please. You have to try to get that vision back and paint her.
-詹姆士 -如果你能画出她健康的样子
- James. - If you paint her all healed,
-她就不会死了 -詹姆士
- then I know she's not gonna die. - James!
蛋离开镇上之后我就没办法预言了
My visions stopped when the egg left Chester's Mill.
求你试试
Please try!
我们不能放弃任何一丝希望
We have to try everything!
詹姆士 我愿为你做任何事请 我是为了你回来这里的
James, I would do anything for you, I came back for you.
但是我的预知能力真的消失了
But my visions are gone.
我不知道我能不能把它找回来
I don't know if I can get them back.
现在梅勒尼快死了 就是因为你搞砸了这一切
Now Melanie is dying because you screwed up,
你把蛋丢下了悬崖
and threw that egg over the cliff.
这些全都是因为你
All of this is your fault!
我这么做只是想让你和你妈妈能逃出这里
I only did that to try to get you and your mom out of here.
看看你做的好事
Look at the mess you've made.
你找到能帮助她的药了吗
Have you found anything to help her, yet?
你似乎不相信我能找到
You sound doubtful that I will.
你说你没找到或许我还能好受点 丽贝卡
Nothing would make me happier, Rebecca.
但是在此期间 你想试试降头术 是么
But in the meantime, you'd like to try what, exactly, a s茅ance?
你觉得我是这么想的
Is that really what you think I believe?
不是
No.
我们都想让她和这个镇子变得更好
We both want what's best for her and this town.
但是当你不停的问为什么穹顶会背叛我们的时候
But while you're busy asking why the dome would betray us,
我却在寻找阻止穹顶杀掉我们的原因
I'm asking how do we stop it before it kills us all.
你难道没有想过只有找到这两个问题的答案才能救我们么
Have you ever considered it might take both questions to save us?
有可能不是呢
Have you ever considered it might not?
-梅勒尼
- - Melanie?
梅勒尼
Melanie?
到底怎么了
Oh, what is going on?
我不知道
I don't know.
她并没有发烧 我觉得这应该是感染
She doesn't have a fever, so I doubt it's an infection.
她的身体正在破损
Her body's falling apart.
肯定是那个蛋发生了什么事
Something must be happening with the egg.
并且伤害到了她
And it's killing her.
可能是很多原因
It could be a bunch of things...
中毒 免疫机能下降
poisoning, autoimmune deficiency...
这是她掉头发的原因么
Is that why her hair is falling out?
可能是
Maybe.
还有什么其他症状么
Any other symptoms?
我只知道
All I know is...
自从蛋消失后 她的身体每况愈下
when the egg disappeared, her health went downhill.
她的血液怎样
How's her blood look?
像她目前一样
Same way she does.
她的血红细胞正在急剧减少
Her red blood cells seem to be disintegrating.
我们得给她输血
A transfusion might buy her some time.
是 但是给她输错血型的血 会要了她的命
Yeah, except if we give her the wrong type, it'll kill her.
我们必须要冒这个险
Well, that's a risk we have to take.
我们没有测血型的装备
We don't have the equipment to type blood.
用利马豆
Lima beans.
什么
Come again?
利马豆中的凝血素
The lectins in lima beans,
它们会在红细胞外壁反应
they react to the surface of red blood cells.
如果我们将它捣碎 和血混在一起
If we mash them up, mix them with the blood,
我们就能分辨血型了
we can determine blood type.
希望输血对她有用
Let's just hope she responds to a transfusion.
为什么会没用
Why wouldn't she?
你以前没有听过这个女孩么
Has anyone told you about this girl?
她怎么了
What about her?
有个奇怪的传言
It's a weird story.
走 安德瑞亚家里应该有利马豆
Come on, I'd bet Andrea has lima beans at her house.
天啊
Oh, God.
她看起来更糟了
She is worse.
我们正在尽我们所能救她
We're doing everything we can.
我也是 你知道我妈的日记在哪里么
Me, too. Uh, do you know where my mom's journal is?
在那个盒子里
It's in that box.
怎么了
Why?
詹姆士
James?
真不敢相信我们竟这么幸运
I can't believe we lucked out like this.
-还是要感谢那些贮藏癖 -是的
- Thank God for hoarders, right? - Right.
你不准备告诉我那个关于梅勒尼的传言么
So, you want to tell me this weird story about Melanie?
哪个部分 她是我高中女朋友
Which part? How she was my high school girlfriend?
还是她25年前就死了 而现在又活过来了
Or how she died 25 years ago, but is now alive again?
-你说什么 -是你问的
- Excuse me? - You asked.
山姆 人不可能死而复生
Sam, people don't die and come back to life.
我是说 死人可以被药物救活
I mean, they can be medically resuscitated,
但是不可能在20年之后
but not after two decades.
但是 她现在就在这儿
And yet, here she is.
并且她确实是我认识的那个女孩
And that is the girl I knew.
你姐姐假装自己死了
Your sister faked her own death,
-我不知道 或许梅勒尼也是
- I-I don't know, maybe Melanie somehow...
-丽贝卡 我亲眼见到她死了
- Rebecca, I saw her die.
我知道死亡是什么样子的
And I know death when I see it.
你傻笑什么 莱尔
Why the stupid grin, Lyle?
我看你竟然在看你妈妈的画作
I see you have an eye now for your mother's artwork.
真正让我疑惑的是为什么她从来没有预见过你
The real question is why she ever had eyes for you.
你妈妈是想要有人来保护她的天赋
Your mother saw that she needed
而不是怀疑它
someone to nurture her gifts, not doubt them.
-所以你就是那个人吗 -反正那个人不会是你父亲
- And you're that someone? - Well, it wasn't your dad.
过去九年她给我寄了这些明信片
She sent me those postcards from the last nine years.
你知道为什么么
You know why?
因为她相信我能理解这些
Because she trusted me to understand them.
你想让我对你做同样的事么
You want me to do the same thing for you?
为什么
Why?
补偿我之前用火钳打了你
To make up for hitting you with the fire poker,
并且偷了日记
and for stealing the journal.
好吧
Okay.
能在这里找到什么 或许能帮助梅勒尼
Find something in here that might help Melanie.
这是你和山姆 妈妈和梅勒尼 对吗
That's you and Sam, my mom and Melanie, right?
是25年前 我们去陨石坑的路上
On our way to the crater, 25 years ago.
-也是梅勒尼死的那晚 -这个不会再发生一次了
- That's the night Melanie died. - That's not gonna happen again.
如果你知道我所知道的 就不会这么说了
If only you knew what I know.
朱尼尔 我们会在穹顶里死去
Junior, we're all gonna die inside this thing.
别说了 看画吧
Just focus on the drawings.
我什么都没找到
I am not seeing anything.
你确定
Are you sure?
你有画过一条新的隧道
You didn't paint a vision of a...
或者洞穴么
of a new tunnel, or a... or a hole in the dome somewhere?
如果我画过 我们现在应该早就找到了
If I had, we would have found it by now.
听着 我们不会因为我把蛋给丢了
Listen, we are not gonna get crushed in this dome
就被穹顶挤碎的
'cause I screwed up and threw that egg over.
这里一定会发生什么
There's got to be something here.
你还好么
You okay?
是的 我很高兴我的血型吻合
Mm-hmm. Yeah, just glad I'm the right blood type.
好的 如果需要帮助就喊我
All right. Give me a shout if you need anything.
谢谢
Thanks.
怎么了
What's going on?
我在给你输血
Um, we're transfusing you.
我会找到你的病因的
I'm gonna find out why you're sick.
找不到原因让你有点抓狂 是么
Not knowing makes you mad, huh?
有点
A little.
我妈妈给我量温度的时候 都会亲吻我的额头
My mom used to kiss my forehead when she took my temperature.
你妈妈也这么做么
Did your mom do that?
我不记得了
I don't remember.
在我八岁的时候她去世了
She died when I was eight.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我想要一个理由
I wanted a reason.
我想知道为什么她会从我身边被带走
Someone to tell me why she was taken from me.
也许有些问题是没有答案
Maybe some questions have no answers.
你说话听起来就像茱莉亚
You sound like Julia.
这是坏事么
Is that such a bad thing?
比起一无所知 梅勒尼
There's a better thing, Melanie...
知道会更好
knowing.
人们总是对这个世界充满好奇
People have always wondered about the world.
为什么会有日升日落
Why the sun rises and sets.
为什么会有春夏秋冬
Why spring turns to summer and then autumn.
为什么爱的人会生病
Why loved ones get sick.
怎样才能让他们好起来
How to make them better.
知道这些问题的答案不会停止人们的好奇
You know, knowing the answers doesn't take away the wonder,
只会让这个世界更加奇妙
it actually makes it more amazing.
那你告诉我 我为什么我快死了
Then tell me why I'm dying.
我不止是生病这么简单 是么
'Cause I'm not just sick, am I?
我快死了
I'm dying.
-听着 -重要的是
- Listen. - All that matters
我第一次死的时候
is, the first time I died,
我是一个人
I was all alone.
现在我有你陪着
Now I have you.
还有茱莉亚
And Julia.
还有我妈妈
And my brother.
就是为了你们 我回来这趟
It was worth coming back
也是值得的
just for that.
又停止了
It's stopping again.
嘿 你的计划生效了
Hey, your plan worked.
我们得把蛋找回来 现在就去
We need the egg back... now!
我们要那颗蛋 现在就要
孩子 你知道我愿意做任何事来帮助你们
Son, you know I'd do anything to help.
但是我不能把蛋给你
But I can't make that happen.
我希望我能帮到你 我不能
好吧 那你的儿子和女儿都将死在这里
All right, well then your son and your daughter die in here.
那么梅勒尼和我都会死的
梅勒尼几年前就消失了
Melanie disappeared years ago.
几年前就已经不见了
不 她现在活着
No. She is alive.
在这里 和我们一起
In here. With us.
还活着 就在这里
不 这不可能
No, that can't be possible.
你在说谎
乔
Joe!
诺瑞 你们两个快点滚出来
Norrie! Get your asses out here!
你怎么知道我们在跟踪你
How'd you know we were following you?
当然知道 秘密行动根本不是你们强项
Yeah, because stealth is not your strong suit.
嘿 听着
Hey, listen.
我要说服我爸相信梅勒尼还活着
I need to convince my dad about Melanie, okay?
你们有照片或者
So, do you have any photos, or...
我有更好的 视频博客
I've got something better... A vlog.
-作为切斯特磨坊镇 -太好了 给他看
As the newest arrival - Yeah, show him.
的最新到访者
in Chester's Mill,
你现在觉得这儿怎么样
how do you like it so far?
-每个人都很悲伤 -是啊
- Everyone's so sad. - Yeah.
有什么是我能帮得上的吗
Is there something I can do to help?
够了
That's enough.
怎么会这样
How?
因为那个蛋把她带回来了
Because that egg brought her back.
如果那个蛋不回到切斯特磨坊镇 她就会死
Without that here in Chester's Mill, she dies,
我们全都得死
and all of us die, too.
又开始了
It's starting again.
我们需要那个蛋 不然我们全都会死
芭比 他没明白 告诉他
Barbie, he isn't getting it. Tell him it's more
那个蛋不只是个东西而已 它是有生命的 它认识我们
than just a thing... it's alive somehow. It knows us.
芭比 那个蛋不想待在穹顶外面 如果他能把蛋还回来
Barbie, the egg is upset being out there. If he gives it back,
-我们就能找到出路 -行 行了 我知
- this could be our way out... - O-Okay, I-I got...
你走开
Get out of here.
走
Go!
我要把蛋还回去 你们从哪里过去的
这样做明智吗
Is this smart?
他可能带他的一整个军队进来
He could bring his whole army through with him.
我们要不然冒这个险 要不然就全都被挤压死在这里
Well, we take that risk or we get crushed to death in here.
告诉他通过他房子地窖的
Tell him to go through the red door
红门过来
of that root cellar at his house.
你房子地窖红门
一切小心
Be careful.
我们从顶点镇过来是通过那个湖
The lake's where we came through from Zenith.
他们出来的时候需要有人在那儿接应
Someone should be there when he shows up.
看 它停了
Look, it's stopping.
-你哪儿也不许去 -我和乔去
- You're not going anywhere. - Joe and I'll go.
好吧 你们俩拿个对讲机再过去湖边
Fine. You guys go get a walkie then head on out to the lake,
而且这次一定要藏好 行吗
but actually hide this time, all right?
别被人发现 我爸出现了就用对讲机联系我
You stay out of sight. When my dad shows up, you radio me.
-去吧 -好的
- Go. - Will do.
觉得你爸真能带着蛋来吗
Think your dad will really go get that egg?
穹顶会让我们知道答案的
The dome'll let us know.
茱莉亚
Julia.
嘿
Hey.
-穹顶停止收缩了 -什么
- The dome stopped contracting. - What?
我见了我爸 说服他把蛋带过来
I met with my dad and I convinced him to get that egg back to us.
真的 他一离开
Literally, soon as he left,
穹顶壁就停止收缩了
the walls just stopped shrinking.
也许穹顶也想让蛋回来
Maybe the dome must have wanted the egg back, too.
当它看到你爸要这样做了
When it saw your dad was gonna make that happen,
-它就给出了信号 -我不敢断言
- it gave us a sign. - I can't say
但是我不知道此外还能怎样解释
for sure, but I don't know how else to explain it.
大家过来 快来
Guys, come here, quick.
梅勒尼
Melanie.
-嗨 -嘿
- Hi. - Hey,
你觉得怎么样
how you feeling?
又活蹦烂跳了
Like myself again.
输血有效了
The transfusion worked.
是啊 输血 还有我们要重新拿到蛋了
Well, that, and we're also getting that egg back.
所以我才恢复了
That's why I'm getting better.
我猜只要那个蛋没事了 你就没事了
I guess when it's okay, you're okay.
听着
Listen...
输血只是一时之计
the transfusion only buys us some time.
她还是病得很重
She's still very sick.
不管怎样 她现在是比之前好多了
Well, whatever it is, she's a hell of a lot better right now
好吗 我觉得这是最重要的
than she was. All right? That's all that matters to me.
哈喽
Hello?
有人听得见吗
Can anyone hear me?
对讲机里面的电池都没电了
All the batteries in these walkies are dead.
这些也是
Ones over here are, too.
芭比 能听见吗
Barbie, can you read me?
-能 诺瑞 我听见了 -太好了
- Yeah, Norrie, I read you. - Great,
只是试一下 等你爸到了我联系你
just checking. We'll radio you when your dad gets here.
收到
Roger that.
好了 我们有对讲机了 可以走了
All right, we got one. We're good to go.
确实可以走了
We sure are.
这是什么
What is that?
-枪啊 -是 乔
- It's a gun. - Yes, Joe,
我知道这是把枪 但是你要拿它干什么
I'm aware it's a gun. But what are you doing with it?
我要带着它
We're taking it with us.
不 你要把它放回去
No, you're gonna put that down.
-别紧张 我看了 它都还没上膛
- Relax, I checked. It's not even loaded.
-是啊 你把它放回抽屉里去
- Yeah, and it's not going to be,
拿该死的钥匙锁上
because you're gonna put it back in that drawer,
-才能保证它不会上膛 -诺瑞
- find the key and lock it the hell up. - Norrie.
乔 上一次也是唯一一次你拿着枪
Joe, the one and only time you have ever held a gun
你差点爆了梅勒尼的头
you almost shot Melanie in the face.
-对 也就是说 实际上没发生 -我们不可以带着它
- Okay, in other words, I didn't. - It's not coming with us.
芭比认为他爸可能很危险
Barbie thinks his dad could be
亨特也是 我们要带着它保护自己
dangerous. Hunter does, too. We need it for protection
以免他爸想做什么对我们不利
in case he tries anything when he gets here.
你想要被保护吗 站我身后啊
You want protection? Just get behind me.
还有 如果唐 芭芭拉带着蛋出现了 他一定会的
Plus, if Don Barbara does show up with the egg, it's gonna be
因为他想帮助我们 而不是伤害我们
because he wants to help us, not hurt us.
-好吧 -我们走吧
- All right. - Let's go.
事情不能就这么结束
It's not gonna end this way. N-Not after all
我们已经经历了这么多
we've been through, not after
穹顶甚至都把你带回到我和朱尼尔的身边
the dome brought you back to me and Junior.
我也希望我能看到些什么来画
I wish I could see something to paint...
-任何能把我们带离这里的东西 -如果我能帮上忙呢
- anything to get us out of here. - What if I can help?
你不能帮到我
You can't fix me.
就像我正在沉没 苦苦寻找岸边
It's like I'm drowning. I'm looking for shore
却只看到一片漆黑
and all I see is darkness.
好吧 你看不到 但是
Okay, you can't see, but...
但是你能感觉到什么吗
but can you feel?
是 我能感觉到
Yes. I feel.
我感觉到孤独
I feel alone.
羞愧
Ashamed.
因为我吗
Of me?
不 因为我自己
No. Of me.
羞愧那么多年前让梅勒尼就那样死去
Ashamed for letting Melanie die all those years ago.
羞愧对你失去信心
Ashamed for losing faith in you.
羞愧离开了我的家人
Ashamed of leaving my family.
不 你没有失去信念
No, you didn't lose faith.
我才是失去信念的那个
I'm the one who lost faith.
我没有理解你的天赋
I didn't understand your gifts.
也 也没理解是穹顶选择了我们
O-O-Or that the dome had chosen us.
现在我理解了
Now I do.
你怎么知道
How can you be sure?
朱尼尔被选中把你带回我身边
Junior was chosen to bring you back to me.
它看到我自愿献祭
The dome chose to save me before I could hang myself.
选泽在我自尽之前解救了我
And it healed all those people
治愈了所有的人
as soon as it saw I was willing to sacrifice.
你被选中了要领导切斯特磨坊镇的人们
You were chosen to lead Chester's Mill.
而你被选中给我指明道路
And you were chosen to show me the way.
看这个 你看到什么
Look at that. What do you see?
-吉姆 -不 你看到什么
- Jim... - No, what do you see?
空白画布
A blank canvas.
你知道我看到什么了吗
You know what I see?
全新的开始
A fresh start.
那么 你原谅我了
So you forgive me?
是 我原谅你了
Yeah, I forgive you.
我们都犯过大错
We've both made some pretty big mistakes.
以前你怎么可能会知道那些画
How could you have known those paintings
会变成现实呢 它们都那么疯狂
would come to life? They were so crazy.
是啊 是挺疯狂的
Yeah, they were.
不 那是起点镇的方尖石塔
No, that's the obelisk in Zenith.
跟梅勒尼一点关系都没有
That doesn't have anything to do with Melanie.
这里一定有什么
There's got to be something in here
表示着梅勒尼的健康
that shows Melanie healthy.
给我 让我试着找找
Here, l-let me try and find something.
这是我和梅勒尼吗
Is that me and Melanie?
这一张里她看着挺不错的
She looks fine in that one.
恩
Mm-mm.
不对 在我看起来
No, the way I see it,
这画的是我和你妈妈一起进入天堂
that's your mother and me entering heaven together.
就像我一直希望的那样
Just like I always hoped.
别那样说
Don't even say that.
是你问的
You asked.
先生 我知道他是你儿子 但我希望你能三思
Sir, I know he's your son, but you need to rethink this.
我的直觉已经带我们走到现在这个程度了
My instincts have gotten us all this far.
你得相信我 马利克
You need to trust me, Malick.
但你甚至都碰不了它
But you can't even touch it.
所有靠近它的人都被伤到了
It's injured anyone that's even gotten near it.
乔
Joe,
有看到我爸的影儿了吗
any sign of my dad yet?
没有他 没有蛋
Not him, not the egg...
什么都没看到
nothing.
好吧 那就再等会儿
All right. Well, give it a little longer.
你见到他的时候 他还记得我吗
When you saw him, did he remember me?
记得 一个父亲永远不会忘了自己的女儿
Yeah, a father doesn't forget his daughter.
我记得他的脸
I remember his face.
就是我见过你的那一天
It was the day I met you.
他看起来似乎很伤心 就像他已经知道了
He seemed sad, like he already knew.
知道什么
He already knew what?
知道如果我们见面
That if we met,
就不会想说再见
we wouldn't want to say good-bye.
好在
Well...
这一次 我们不需要说再见
This time, we won't have to.
芭芭拉先生 不要
Mr. Barbara, no.
是时候做我该做的事了
Time to do what I need to do.
-怎么回事 -先生 你需要留在这
- What the hell? - Sir, that needs to remain here.
-让他们退下 马利克 -我听命于人 就像你一样
- Tell 'em to back off, Malick. - I take orders, just like you.
梅勒尼
Melanie?
我怎么了
What's happening to me?
冷静下来 山姆
Stay calm. Sam?!
我以为他答应了要帮我们
I thought he promised to help.
没事的 坚持住 梅勒尼 山姆
All right, hang in there, Melanie. Sam?!
-怎么了 -她不能好好呼吸了
- What happened? - She was having trouble breathing.
她刚刚晕过去
She just passed out.
坚持住
Come on.
我知道我们搞砸了
I know we've screwed up.
一次又一次
Over and over again.
但是就算是发生了这一切
But even with everything that's happened,
我仍然选择相信你是在保护我们
I still choose to believe you're trying to protect us.
我以为当你
I think that when you...
停止移动时 是在用你自己的方式
stopped moving, that was your way of giving all of us
给我们另一次机会 因此我要再求你一件事情
another chance, so I need to ask you for one more thing.
求你救救梅勒尼
Please help Melanie.
她应该活着
She deserves to live.
这里的每一个人都该活着
Everyone in here does.
你说过 我是被选中的人
You said that I was chosen.
那么 如果我是 那一定是为了完成什么事情
Well, if I was, then that has to be for something.
所以 如果有人必须死 那就让我死好了
So if someone has to die, then let it be me.
求求你 别再带走他们中的任何一人了
Just please, don't take any more of them.
-打扰一下
- - Sorry.
-怎么了 -开始起作用了
- How's it going? - It started working.
我的预知能力回来了
A vision came through.
-你画了两幅画吗 -没有 只有一副
- You painted two? - No, just one.
画中有显示我该怎么拯救整个镇吗
Does it show me how to save the town?
不 会比朱尼尔想要的多更多
No, it's more what Junior wanted.
-你得继续画 -我不行
- You need to keep painting then. - I can't.
什么意思
Well, what's it mean?
我不确定 但我想它告诉我们该怎么就梅勒尼
I'm not sure, but I think it tells us how to save Melanie.
那八个人能治好她
The eight hands are to heal her?
现在我知道为什么我要山姆和莱尔跟我一起回来了
Now I know why I wanted Sam and Lyle to come back with me.
八个人 四个过去的人 四个新人
The eight hands... four old, four new...
共同努力能把她治好
working together to make her well again.
是 但是安琪已经死了 现在该只有七个人 谁是第八个人呢
Yeah, but Angie's dead, so there's only seven. Who's the eight?
-我不知道 -不要紧
- I don't know. - Doesn't matter.
穹顶知道的就了
The dome knows.
还有 只要是你画出来的 就会成真的
Besides, if you painted it, it must be true.
-我们该从哪里找起 -学校
- Where do we start? - The school.
好 走吧
All right, let's go.
这是我第一次见到你呆坐着
It's the first time I've seen you sit still.
梅勒尼怎么样了
How's Melanie?
她回复到原来的样子了
She's back to the way she was.
我不明白 山姆
I just don't get it, Sam.
为什么输血起不来作用
Why the transfusion didn't work?
为什么她有好转 为什么好转之后又病了
Why she got better, why she got sick again.
大部分原因在于她本身吧
Most of all, who she even is.
她时隔多年才回来
Her coming back after all these years contradicts
违反了物理学生物学的定律
every law of physics, biology.
而那是 那是我一直以来都相信的存在
That's-that's everything that I have ever believed in.
科学无法解释世间一切事物
Science doesn't have every answer.
我只是没有办法像你和茱莉亚那样屈服
Well, I just can't give up like you and Julia.
那不是屈服 而是释然
It's not giving up. It's letting go.
屈服和释然是不同的
There's a difference.
有什么不同
Which is?
知道并且接受世界上有些事情
Knowing there are things
是你所不知道的
you don't know and still being okay with it.
走吧 你和我
Come on, what do you say
我们一起去面对这个不确定事件怎么样
you and I go face this uncertainty together?
也只能这样了 对吧
Guess that's an answer I'll have to accept, right?
梅勒尼在哪里
Where's Melanie?
问这个干什么 -我花了一幅预知画
Why? - I painted a vision.
可能显示了我们要怎么救她
It may show us how to save her.
你相信这个
And you're in on this?
重要的是你要相信我的妻子
All that matters is you believe my wife.
如果我们能救梅勒尼 那我们就能救这个镇
If we can save Melanie, we can save this town.
那么 我们最好动作快点
Well, we better hurry. The
穹顶又在收缩了 这一次收缩的速度比之前都快
dome is closing in again, this time, even faster.
他没有出现在湖边
So he didn't show up at the lake.
没有 但是波林觉得她找了治疗梅勒尼的方法
No, but Pauline thinks there's a way to heal Melanie.
不用唐把蛋带来吗
Without Don bringing the egg?
波林要我们一起 老成员和新成员一起去
Pauline wants us all together... the old and new hands.
我能去吗
Can I go?
你都大老远跑来了
You've come this far.
-你准备好了吗 -是的 随时可以
- You ready to go? - Yeah, just tell us when.
-你也一起去吗 -嗯
- You're coming, too? - Mm-hmm.
对这个不科学的世界里所有事情的不确定激起你的兴趣了
Wasn't sure anything this unscientific would interest you.
如果有方法能够治疗梅勒尼 那我要去见识见识
Well, if this is a way to heal Melanie, I want to see it.
也许我们都是对的 茱莉亚
Maybe we can both be right, Julia.
是真的吗
Is it true?
穹顶真的收缩得更快了吗
The dome's contracting faster now?
这也正是我们需要加快动作的原因
It's exactly why we need to hurry.
所以我们爸爸没有做到他答应我们的事
So, our dad didn't do what he promised.
重要的是我答应了什么
All that matters is what I promise.
我们会让你好起来的
We're gonna make you better.
你确定这能帮到她
You sure this'll help her?
我只能确定我们必须试一试
I'm only sure that we have to try.
不管今天会发生什么事情
No matter what happens today,
我爱你 詹姆士
I love you, James.
永远别忘记
Never forget that.
什么意思
What do you mean?
多年前 我抛下了你
Years ago, I left you.
那是个错误
It was a mistake.
再也不会发生那样的事了
It's not gonna happen again.
我原谅你 妈妈 但为什么你现在要说这个
I forgive you, Mom, but why are you saying this?
-没事吧 -我们很好
- Everything okay here? - We're fine.
我们准备开始吧
Let's get ready to head out.
还有 詹姆士 试着原谅他吧
And, James, please try to forgive him.
他在这里做什么
What the hell's he doing here?
你知道的 他是最初的四个人之一
You know he's one of the original four.
今天天气真好 很适合做好事
It's a great day to do something wonderful.
离我的家人远点
Stay away from my family.
我回来切尔斯特磨坊镇的时候
When I came back to Chester's Mill,
我梦见梅勒尼就在中央
I had a dream of seeing Melanie in the center.
把她放在那里
Put her there.
等等
Hold on.
把她放着这里
Put her here.
嘿
Hey.
嘿 你会没事的
Hey, you're gonna be fine.
然后呢 现在要做什么
So, what now?
我不是很确定
I'm not exactly sure.
那幅画太抽象了
The painting was more symbolic.
-她快不能呼吸了
- Well, she's barely breathing.
-芭比 别吵她
- BIG JIM: Barbie, let her do her thing.
所有人围着她 跪下
All hands surround her. Everyone kneel down.
朱尼尔 你抓着她的手
Junior, you grab her hand.
其他人 准备把一只手放在她身上
Everyone else, get ready to lay a hand on her.
好了 现在
Okay, now.
什么事都没有发生
Nothing's happening.
- 我们 我们是不是做错了
- Are we... are we doing something wrong?
-吉姆 也许你是对的
- Jim, maybe you're right.
没有安琪 我们人员不齐
We don't have enough hands without Angie.
-我们必须治好她 -我很抱歉 我正在努力
- We have to heal her. - I'm sorry. I'm trying.
嘿 她怎么了
Hey, what's happening to her?
-她在接收我们的能量 -八个人没有全部到齐
- She's seizing. - PAULINE: We can't do it, not
我们没有办法救她 我们只有七个人
without all the eight hands. We only have seven.
等等 我们有八个人的
Wait. We do have eight.
梅勒妮算两个人
Melanie counts as two hands.
过去的她 还有现在的她
The girl she was in the past, and the girl she is now.
代替安琪
Replacing Angie?
但是她没有办法一次充当两个人
She can't be two people at once.
不 不是两个人
No, not two people.
是不同时间里的同一个人 在过去和在现在
The same person in two different times, past and present.
按量子力学理论 一个物体
Quantum physics says an object...
一个物体能在同一时间出现在两个不同的地方
An object can be in two places at once.
就是这样 所以 如果梅勒尼是过去和现在的桥梁
Exactly. So if Melanie is the bridge between past and present,
-那么第七和第八个人就是 有人牵着她的另一只手
- the seventh and eighth hand... - Someone take her other hand.
詹姆士 你是现在的人
James, you're the hand from the present.
山姆 你是25年前和她交往的人 你来牵她的手
Sam, you dated her 25 years ago. You do it.
其他人再次把你们的一只手放在她身上
Everyone else lay a hand on her again.
有作用了吗
Is it working?
她停止接收能量了
Her seizures stopped.
不要放手
Don't let go.
嘿 嘿
Hey! Hey!
-怎么回事 -冷静点 莱尔 没事的
- What the hell is happening? - Steady, Lyle. It's okay.
没事的 莱尔
It's okay, Lyle.
她要醒了
She's waking!
梅勒尼 你没事吧
Melanie, are you okay?
她看起比我好
She looks better than okay to me.
波林
Pauline.
这太美好了
It's so beautiful.
哦
Oh.
-梅勒尼 -嘿
- Melanie! - Hey!
-不
- - SAM: No!
-梅勒尼 抓住我的手 抓住我的手
- Melanie. Grab my hand! Grab my hand! -
拉紧她 -我在用力了
Hold on to her. - I'm trying!
不要让她走
Don't let her go!
加油 抓紧 抓紧
Okay, hold on! Hold on!
-芭比 -抓紧她 不要松手
- Barbie. - Hold onto her. Don't let go!
-梅勒尼
- - Melanie!
-不
- No. -
-梅勒尼
- Oh! - Melanie!
-她去哪里了 -我不知道
- Where did she go? - I don't know.
-我们得跟上去 -不 不 不
- We have to go after her! - No, no, no.
嘿 你不知道那是通向哪里的
Hey, you don't know where that goes.
你们不也什么都不知道就跳进那里 你们都干过的
You jumped out there not knowing, both of you did!
对 但是 菲尔跳下去之后立马死了
Yeah, and then, Phil jumped and died instantly.
这里可能也会发生同样的事情
Same thing could happen here!
他说得对 朱尼尔 经一事长一智
He's right, Junior. We got to be smart
先弄清楚怎么回事再说
about this, figure it out first.
你预知画的就是这样吗
Is this the way you painted it?
我以为它显示了她被治好了 但是
I thought it showed her healed, but...
等等 -波林
Wait. - Pauline!
-波林 -在我的梦里
- Pauline! - In my dream,
我看见梅勒尼消失了 但我不知道它指的就是那个
I saw Melanie disappear, but I didn't know it meant that.
也许她现在还活着
Maybe she's alive somehow.
-你都看见了 这是我的错 -没有人怪你
- You saw what happened. It's my fault! - No one's blaming you.
你只是努力想要帮忙
You tried to help.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
波林
Pauline?
你知道为什么吗
You know why?
因为她该和我在一起的 吉姆
'Cause she's supposed to be with me, Jim.
永远都该和我在一起
Always has been supposed to be with me.
原来那些红漆 是我的血
The red paint... it was my blood.
-什么 什么意思 -穹顶要去我
- What-what do you mean? - The dome
牺牲
wanted me to sacrifice.
这样我和她就能一起到天堂了
So that she and I could be in heaven together.
永远在一起 我们永远在一起
Forever. Us. Us.
你 你抓住我了
You g... you got me.
你抓住我了
You got me.
-噢
- Oh, g... -
噢
Oh. Oh...
谢谢你 吉姆
Thank you, Jim.
谢谢你
Thank you.
呃哼
Uh-huh.
波林 波林
Pauline. Pauline.
为什么
Why?
得到的时候 失去的时候 撕裂的时候
A time to gain  A time to lose  A time to rend
缝补的时候 爱的时候 恨的时候 -为什么
A time to sew A time for love A time for hate  - Why?!
-和平的时候
- A time for peace  -
我发誓 这真的不晚
I swear it's not too late.